I work in Tradfi. I work with a lot of
people that hate Bitcoin. Hate's a very
strong word. They hate it. They hate it.
What's the percentage of Trady people
that hates Bitcoin?
This might get me into trouble. Uh,
welcome to the jungle cuz there's a lot
of people that come in and fail. It's
very capitalistic. It's very kill or get
killed. What happens in the ETF space is
there it's we call it a spaghetti cannon
in many cases. They just throw a ton of
stuff at the wall and whatever sticks
they leave it up. There was like a
Christian ETF. There was like an
earthquake ETF. There were like there's
an UFO ETF. What was the most random ETF
you've ever seen? Honestly, the there's
one that's
been extremely early. Like a lot of
people think these Bitcoin ETFs launch
and it's like, okay, now every adviser
can just buy them. That is not how it
works. There's a whole due diligence
process. Often times it take it's going
to create a lot of demand. So I think
that's the ne next wave of demand
potentially for for Bitcoin. The biggest
holders of these Bitcoin ETFs
specifically and Ethereum ETFs, they're
hedge funds. And what are they doing?
One, Ethereum ETFs, like if you compare
them to the launch of the Bitcoin ETFs,
which is the greatest launch of all time
in fund history essentially in ETF
history specifically. Okay, the Ethereum
ETFs were kind of a failure. Do you see
people asking for these products? Do we
need a Doge ETF? Who's buying them? So,
the largest holder of the Bitcoin ETFs
as a category is hedge funds. The next
biggest holders, they control trillions
of dollars in assets. They are the
biggest users of ETFs. There have been
multiple 70 80% pullbacks. A lot of ETFs
will hold Japanese, Taiwanese, Chinese
stocks in the US. And the way the ETF
works is
[Music]
like, is the crypto bare market about to
end anytime soon? We'll find out with
the next guest, James Ciphford, ETF
analyst at Bloomberg Intelligence.
Welcome to the show, James. I'm David
Lynn. I'm Bonnie. Thanks for having me,
guys. James, let's talk about uh market
action up until March, middle of March
here. date. We're speaking uh mid-March.
What's going on? Yeah, I mean the if you
look at crypto broadly or specifically
Bitcoin and all of the positive news
actions you've seen since Trump got
elected, granted there was a run up from
about 70 to over 100, but like we're
still seeing positive news action after
positive news action. The underlying
fundamentals just based on the
regulatory environment has been
extremely positive for the whole space.
And still Bitcoin is went from 109 down
to 75, right, as of the time we're
talking about this. And I think a lot
all of that really just has to do with
risk assets, right? You you mentioned
the S&P's down uh S&P was down 10% at it
at its peak to trough so far. Uh small
caps in the US specifically down 20%,
mag 7 down 20%. So like I think this
whole move in Bitcoin specifically is
more to do with you know the fact that
things are just selling off globally.
There's a deleveraging u momentum trade
has fallen off a bit. Uh, so I think
this has nothing to do with like the
idiosyncrasies of Bitcoin itself and I
think it's also probably healthy for
some of crypto. I mean some of the froth
that we saw in like memecoins and stuff
like that in crypto more broadly they're
likely they might not come back you know
but Bitcoin and some of the other crypto
assets that have real utility they are
this could be a wash out and they'll
they should theoretically come back if
they have some real end to use case.
This is a chart you worked on cumulative
Bitcoin ETF flows topped at $40 billion
a couple months ago. uh again
correlation or causation here with the
markets. So, it's funny there. We're
we've seen about five and a half
billion. Actually, no, it's less. It's
about five billion now because money
started coming back into the Bitcoin ETF
since since they launched, right? So,
they launched and they took in 40
billion at their peak in the beginning
of February. What mo people are like,
"Oh, everyone's selling all these like
these these retail traders that are
buying these ETFs. They're just
dumping." Which I don't think is what's
happening. One of my most read pieces so
far year to date is basically the
biggest holders of these Bitcoin ETFs
specifically and Ethereum ETFs, they're
hedge funds. And what are they doing?
One, yeah, maybe some of them are
holding it because they have long-term
belief in Bitcoin. Uh maybe it's a
tactical trade, but what a lot of the
money that's come in specifically from
like dece December through the end of
January, it was the basis trade. There
were times on a daily basis where like a
basis trade is basically where you sell
the futures forward. So you're selling
the futures, you're selling your Bitcoin
exposure at one price and to offset that
position, you're buying the spot Bitcoin
ETFs. That way everything's in the
traditional financial rails. you don't
have to worry about the DeFi ecosystem,
the DeFi rails, and your your exposure
to Bitcoin is zero. It's delta neutral.
And the yield on that at points in
December and January and even into early
February, we're well into double digits,
sometimes 25% on an annualized yield
basis. So like you had, if you're a
Tradfi manager and you're looking at
this and be like, I can risk free get
double digit returns, I'm in. So they
were piling in. What happened starting
around February
10thish, that basis trade, that yield
went through the floor. It went to
single digits. So all of a sudden, all
that money that poured in, the billions
that poured in to take advantage of that
basis trade, that basis trade is being
unwound. We see in the open interest in
the futures market. And so a lot of
money that came out, that 5 a.5 billion
I was talking about. I have a I'm
there's no way to know for sure. I will
bet a huge chunk of that was those hedge
funds, those people taking advantage of
the basis trade. Obviously, some of it
is, you know, price is down, people are
selling, weak hands, what have you, but
I think a lot of it was the basis trade.
We'll come back to the flows later.
Bonnie, what about the um Ethereum spot
ETF? How is it doing? Yeah, so like when
the Ethereum ETFs launched, we got a lot
of flak online on crypto, Twitter, and
Twitter in general because we didn't
have high expectations. We thought they
would do 15% of the flows that Bitcoin
ETFs did. And the ETH on the internet
were very mad at us for saying that. And
ironically, our 15% was like way
overestimating what actually happened,
at least for the first few months,
because they had net outflows through
basically Trump's election. And then
Trump got elected and money started
pouring into the Ethereum ETF. So they
went from on a net basis about like 600
700 million in outflows to now being
over three billion in net inflows. So
that's like a 4 billion swing just from
Trump's election. We have seen outflows
in the same way, but not to the same
level that we saw in the Bitcoin ETFs.
Uh so for the most part Ethereum ETFs
like if you compare them to the launch
of the Bitcoin ETFs which is the
greatest launch of all time in fund
history essentially in ETF history
specifically um yeah okay the Ethereum
ETFs were kind of a failure but if you
look at them as like how did they do
compared to other ETF launches they've
done fantastically the problem is
they've taken in all that money they
launched with about 10 billion in assets
in July they have like six seven billion
in assets now despite taking in all
those billions in dollars it's because
Ethereum has not had a good time on the
price side of things. So, the way that
assets are driven, they're driven by two
things. Either the performance of the
underlying asset, whatever they're
holding, and flows. Flows look great for
Ethereum ETS for the most part since the
Trump election. Price obviously does not
look very good. So, you actually have
like lower assets even though you've
seen $3 billion in inflows. How is it
being pitched to customers? Is it
digital oil or is it app store? Yeah. So
that is a very good question and it's
one of the things why we were concerned
with the demand for the Ethereum ETFs.
Bitcoin has a really easy narrative. It
is digital gold. It is a digital store
of value. It's digital scarcity. It's a
medium of it's a medium of exchange on
the internet particularly for higher
dollar amounts. Like that's very easy to
describe. What is Ethereum is very
different. And I honestly you need to
ask the issuers how they're pitching
this to advisers and institutions that
are looking to own these ETFs. I I know
Matt Hogan of Bitwise talks about saying
like it's more like he views a lot of
other crypto including Ethereum. It's
like Bitcoin is one thing. Even the US
government says that right? Bitcoin is
one thing. All these other crypto assets
are something else. And I view them more
like a tech growth play. Like they could
be the technology that's the backbone of
a whole bunch of different things where
there's tokenization. But I I don't know
how it's being pitched. In my mind I
think of as like a digital app store,
the underlying DeFi layer potential um a
blockchain ecosystem, DeFi ecosystem.
But Bitcoin has really no competitors in
the sense of that digital store value.
Despite Ethereum trying to be that
whereas Ethereum has a lot of
competitors on the DeFi side of things,
whether it's Salana, Appto, you name it.
There's like a whole bunch of different
people trying to play in that space. Um,
and it's going to take a long time to
figure out who the winners are. Are you
actually doing a panel here um entitled
the next wave of institutional crypto
products? You just referenced a few of
these products. Can you go into more
detail? Yeah, I mean, well, what the
main one that I cover obviously is the
ETF side of things, but overall this
there's this general um trend of these
traders becoming or tradi institutions
becoming bridges between the trady rails
and the DeFi rails. So, I think of when
you think of these ETFs that are holding
crypto assets, the way to think about
them is it's like a bridge. It's taking
this online digitally native asset
whether it's Ethereum or Bitcoin or
Salana or XRP whatever you whatever you
want to call it and it's packaging it
and putting it on the traditional
financial rails. Then we have other
things where we see Wisdom Tree is a
smaller issuer Van uh Black Rockck uh
Franklin Templeton they're doing the
exact opposite. They're taking things or
you know Circle and Tether they're
taking these tradi assets whether it is
dollars money market funds potentially
even stocks and bonds down the line real
estate. the goal is going to be taking
these tradi real world assets and
putting them on the DeFi rails and I
think a lot of these institutions we're
talking about are going to be building
those bridges for that to happen. So
that's a lot of the stuff that we're
going to be talking about on my panel
later today and it's just like how do
you do that tokenization of real world
assets all those different things and
also not everyone wants an ETF. Some
people want to have their own custody of
their own assets. as an institution, you
still have to have relationship with a
custody manager because if you're
managing hundreds of millions of dollars
or even just millions of dollars and you
just lose your keys, like that's not a
good answer for your bosses on like how
you lost things. So, you have real a lot
of people like think not your keys, not
your coins, but in this in in the
institutional world, you need contract
set up, right? You need to have a
relationship with somebody who can who
knows is professionally dealing with
these things. And also, you want to have
somebody to blame if something goes
wrong rather than I lost the keys or I
lost my hardware wallet, something along
those lines, right? So, um, that's one
thing that people in the crypto world
like tend to misunderstand, but people
in, you know, finance in general kind of
get it. Somebody else needs to be to
blame other than me for allocating to
this asset class. You also talk about
altcoins ETFs a lot. Um, what is it?
XRP, um, Salana, Doge, Litecoin.
What are your thoughts? Yeah, I mean,
we're pretty confident that everything
you just mentioned is going to have a
spot ETF this year in 2025 in the US.
there already exists in eur in in uh
Europe uh for many of the ones you
mentioned. Um we think we're going to
see them all approved here in the US. Um
Salana futures ETF which I think we we
know for a fact there is some demand for
futures products but not nearly as much
as there is for spot futures. It's just
more complicated. You have to roll them.
They're derivatives. They're not exactly
easy to explain. Um so we're going to
see one of those launch in the next week
probably. And we just saw CME futures on
Salana list on Monday of this week. Um,
we think we're going to see other
futures of these other assets launch. We
think we're going to see a lot of these
ETFs launch. Um, Litecoin is, I think, a
slam dunk. We we were very confident
they were going to get approved. Uh, we
still are. Um, so we think all of those
things are going to get approved. The
question more so is like how much demand
is there for a Litecoin ETF or an XRP
ETF or you name it. Uh, and we think we
we don't think it's going to be nothing.
Like I said, it kind of goes back to the
Ethereum side of things. If you compare
it to the Bitcoin ETF launch, okay.
Yeah, maybe it looks like a failure on a
comparative basis, but like you can
still run successful ETFs with just $50
to $100 million in assets. They're still
profitable products. They're still
traded. People will still use them. Um,
so that that's overall that's our
assumption what's going to happen with a
lot of these altcoin ETFs. And even
still, if you're an issuer that
specializes in this, think Grayscale for
example or Bitwise, you're going to want
to have a lot of these altcoins out
there because you don't want to go to,
you know, you're talking to advisers or
institutions about all these ETFs and
you're like, "Oh, well, this other
issuer has this ETF. Why don't you have
it?" It's just easier to kind of have it
on your like uh your menu, your
offering. That way, if people want it,
they can get exposure to it. And then
one of the other things that often
happens in the ETF space is like as
price goes up, it kind of brings demand.
So, if we see some of these altcoins
really rallying, you're likely going to
see money from retail and other people
kind of pour in and use these ETFs to
get that exposure. Do you see people
asking for these products? I was going
to ask, do we need a Doge ETF? Who's
buying them?
Institutions. So this goes back to like
what what I was talking about with the
fact that a lot the the largest holder
of the Bitcoin ETFs as a category as of
the end of December. We have data from
13F filings in the US is hedge funds.
They own like 10 just under 11 billion
worth of those Bitcoin ETFs when they
had $15 billion or 100 billion in
assets. So they're a huge holder. The
next biggest holder is investment
advisors which is likely the biggest
area of growth for these ETFs.
investment advisers, the people managing
other people's money at wirehouses, at
wealth platforms, they control trillions
of dollars in assets, they are the
biggest users of ETFs. So, do I see them
saying we need a 2% allocation to a
Dogecoin ETF? No, probably not. Maybe
Salana if they think it's competing with
Ethereum, maybe some of these other
coins that are and layer 1 chains that
are trying to compete, possibly, right?
But what you also have to realize is we
only know like 27% of the holders of the
Bitcoin ETFs. The rest are either retail
or offshore entities. A lot of it, and
if you've talked to anyone, it's a lot
of retail money that are in these
products. We see a lot of demand for
super leveraged ETFs, derivatives based
ETFs. People love to gamble,
specifically in the US, right? So, if
you're trading these things, you might
have interest in these ETFs because you
just want to trade them. And it's just
easier to do it with your Robin Hood or
Schwab or whatever account, Fidelity
account, if that you can trade them on
those platforms rather than going to a
Coinbase or Kraken or Gemini, you name
it. So, will there be a lot of demand?
Probably not. Will there be people
trading these things? Yes, I would. Yes.
The some of the plenty of these things
will find success and they'll find
enough assets. When the Bitcoin ETS
launched, they were like, there's no way
all 11 of these are going to survive.
All 11 of them have way more than enough
assets to survive long term to be
profitable for the people that launch
them. Granted, if Bitcoin goes down to,
you know, 20K from here, maybe it won't
be profitable then, but at the rate that
Bitcoin is growing and has grown, it's
it's still profitable to have them. I
think this may speak to a broader change
in the ETF landscape because when you
think about the history of ETFs, you go
back to the '90s with the spiders,
right? They're the large index funds and
now we have a potential Doge or Litecoin
ETF. I mean the buyers and holders and
traders of ETFs, how have their profiles
changed over the last 25 years? That is
a fantastic question. It's something our
team is always talking about, right? So
what you also have to realize is the way
reason ETFs were launched wasn't for buy
and hold long-term investing. Like the
creation of them was to offset like
different derivatives products that were
launched in the 80s that caused like
Black Monday essentially. So, like the a
debrief from the um I think it was the
SEC about like Black Monday and what
caused the flash crash back then. That's
what was the colonel that like created
the ETF. They were saying if something
actually held the underlying assets and
traded, it would be better than these
derivatives products that caused like
basically a leverage unwind in the in
the in the traditional financial markets
that we're used to seeing in crypto. But
it was a big problem when you have that
happening in Trafi. That's what ETFs
were created. They were trading
vehicles. So, the benefit of an ETF is
really that you you can use it. Your
adviser is using it. Uh your grandmother
might be buying it as long-term and hold
and a hedge fund might be using it to go
in and out on a daily basis. Market
makers are using it to pick up BIPS. And
when you have like all these different
ecosystem players playing in one space,
it creates for a really efficient cheap
market that gives everyone the same
exposure. In mutual funds and hedge
funds, it's like siloed rappers. You
have a certain amount of money. You need
to be sophisticated to a certain extent.
There's costs in doing that. ETFs bring
everyone together. But what's what's so
basically that's one thing to answer
your question is leverage ETFs have
always been around since the the you
know basically thou mid 2000s. They have
always been a small niche part of the
ETF world. People love to trade. They
love to gamble. What's more recent is a
lot of these derivatives ETFs because
there's some rules that made it a lot
easier to hold derivatives. We also have
single stock leverage ETFs that are
huge. But you also have to realize like
as an AUM basis, they're not that big.
They're like they're like very much in
the satellite portion of the ETF world
in the US, but people love to trade and
there's not it they trust the ETF rapper
to work well. So essentially the the
Dogecoin ETFs I kind of and these other
ones I kind of feel like in the same
realm as I do like some of these single
stock leverage ETFs. They're trading
vehicles. They're gambling and there's
nothing wrong with that and they give
you the protections that the ETF wrapper
kind of affords you uh in there. So, I I
think overall it's just like the vast
majority of the assets are in the things
like an S&P 500 ETF or an aggregate bond
ETF like long-term buy and hold types of
investments and these other things.
There's been a push to like say they're
not ETFs, call them ETPs or ETIs,
exchange traded instruments and things
like that so that people don't confuse
them with the safe nature of, you know,
diversified exposure. But there's
nothing wrong with them. uh one of Dave
Na who's a legend in the ETF industry is
calling them white hat products versus
black hat products almost like uh uh
hackers in the sense that these things
are like it's basically these issuers
are trying to make a ton of money
because they know people are going to
trade them and they're addicted to
trading volatility. I saw on your
Twitter post that you said um I can't
remember if it was you or Eric. Um you
guys said Bitcoin is down but the
holders are not selling. The ETF holders
are not selling because they are baby
boomers.
Yeah. So um one of the things that we
got flack for and a lot of people were
saying before the ETF's launch was that
everyone's going to be paper hands. They
were going to sell at the first sign of
a selloff. We had a massive sell off in
August. We basically saw no money coming
out. We're seeing it. We're seeing it
now. Everyone's talking about 5 billion
came out of these ETFs. You got to
realize that's like less than 5% of the
assets, right? So like at the start of
this, there was 115 billion in these
ETFs. $120 billion in these ETFs. We've
seen 5 billion come out, you hear 5
billion, that's a lot. But when you when
you put a denominator on there, it's
like, oh, that's not that big of a deal.
And it's because one, we people who are
buying these ETFs know what they're
buying. Like I hope the people buying
Bitcoin ETFs know there have been
multiple 70 80% pullbacks, right? So
they know the volatility. They should
understand this. And like I said, even a
lot of the flows that we've seen coming
out, my view, as I said, is more from
the people that were playing the basis
trade than necessarily these boomers
that are putting this as a 1% 2%
allocation in their portfolio. If you're
an adviser and you're putting this in a
client portfolio, you're not putting it
at 20% of the portfolio. They're not
looking this and being like, I'm getting
crushed here. It's more like, okay, we
had a 2 or 3% allocation. It's gone down
or gone up and they're going to
rebalance around that. So, as prices
come down, you'll probably see money
pour in from the advisers who are trying
to maintain an allocation. The flip side
is when you see price go up, say we go
up to 120, 150, some crazy number like
that. You're likely to see some money
from advisers that will come out.
Granted, retail when money pours up, it
tend you tend to see money pour into an
ETF, but you'll see advisers rebalancing
around their target allocation. they'll
they'll say I want 5% 2% and if it runs
up because of price they'll sell to get
back to it. If it falls down because of
prices collapsing they'll they'll buy to
get back up there. So that's overall my
view. But for the most part ETF holders
they know that it's such a good deal.
The fees are really good compared to
other products particularly in the DeFi
world and crypto world. So they're
holding and again for the most part this
is likely a satellite position in their
portfolio. Like if the S&P 500 was down
30% and that's 20% of their portfolio,
that hurts. Bitcoin down 30 20% and it's
a 2% allocation, it's not that big of a
deal. Is there enough liquidity for
stuff like Litecoin or Dogecoin to even
create an ETF? I mean, if there isn't
enough, then the creation redemption
process isn't going to work very well,
and then we're going to get huge
discounts or premiums to NAV. Yeah. So I
would say the ETF rapper is so good that
we're not going to see huge discounts of
premiums in NAV. what we the way we look
at things. So like a lot of ETFs will
hold you know um uh Japanese, Taiwanese,
Chinese stocks in the US and the way the
ETF works is like we call there's a
premium and discount and what we like to
refer to that as so like if the ETF is
trading above the value of the
underlying assets or below it we refer
to that as the arbitrage band because
there's so many people the Jane streets
the virtues the hedge funds the citadels
if there's a dislocation there grayscale
Bitcoin ETF was trading at a huge like
premium at some point well it wasn't
isn't an ETF. Okay, when it became an
ETF, that premium collapsed to 1 and a
half% as soon as it launched. Granted,
it still traded at a slight premium once
it was an ETF, but when you can go in,
so the the benefit of an ETF, the the
creation of the ETF basically came from
this guy Nate Most. They got the idea,
like I said, from that SEC debrief. It
was a huge long massively page paper
about like what happened in the 1987
crash. and his idea, he came from a
commodities background and he had this
idea of something called commodities
warehouse receipts. It was basically
like if you had gold or grain or oil,
the way you would trade that is you
would put that into a commodities
warehouse, they would charge a fee to
hold it and they would give you receipts
of paper that says you own this much
gold here, you own this much oil. And
rather than like moving the physical
gold and oil, you could just move those
paper receipts around. That's how a lot
of commodities trading happened back in
the day. And the idea was why don't we
just do that with stocks? And that was
the first S&P 500 ETF, right? Uh
actually the first ETF was in Canada,
but that's a side story. Um so that's
all this is. So if at any point you can
hand over the underlying asset and get
back shares of the
ETF, that means there's an arbitrage
mechanism to always make sure things
stay in line. So when you see in an ETF
that's operating properly where the
creation mechanism is able to be
activated and used when you see premiums
and discounts that's often an indication
that the ETF is pricing what the actual
market is. So like for example in 2020
during the depths of like the pullback
this is going real niche but like high
yield mun bond ETF high yield munis are
very illquid they thing was trading at a
20% discount and people are like the ETF
is broken. No, what was broken was the
nav of the underlying bonds because
there was no trading. And if you called
a Muni bond trader, it was like no bid,
no bid, which means no one was buying
these things. So if you were trading the
ETF, the people making markets in those
ETFs, there was they couldn't get a they
couldn't get a mark in them, right? So
they're they're trading at a 20%
discount because that's where the actual
market is. So if we're talking about
Litecoin, for the most part, these
people are going to be able to source
liquidity. And if they can't, the ETF is
probably going to be an indicative
valuation of where the price is in the
underlying asset because there's so much
liquidity. The infrastructure in the US
around trading these ETFs is so strong
that if there is a huge premium or
discount, there's likely something else
going on. The other thing I would say is
the reason we got the Bitcoin and
Ethereum ETFs approved was based on the
liquidity of the underlying futures
market saying they could seek out fraud
and manipulation, understand what's
going on there. I don't think that was
necessary. They could have done a
surveillance sharing agreement with with
the likes of Coinbase, Gemini, Kraken,
Binance, you name it. And that's enough
to surveil the underlying market. So, I
think ultimately that's what they're
going to lean on when they approve these
things. Yes, potentially having futures
markets that are regulated by the CFTC
will be helpful, but I think the
liquidity will be there. And if it's
not, it'll be very interesting to watch.
But for the most part, they're going to
tap whatever liquidity they can. And if
a ton of money pours into the Litecoin
ETF, for example, and you don't worried
about liquidity, what's going to happen
when it doesn't matter. They have to buy
the underlying asset. It's just like
buying the underlying asset. At some
point, that money comes in, whether it's
at a delay or it happens
instantaneously. Those dollars need to
get exposed to Litecoin. So, what's
going to happen to the underlying asset?
It's going to get bit up because they're
going to go wherever they can. And
demand is going to create new supply.
Like, as price goes up, more people are
going to come into market willing to
sell. Larry Frink from uh Black Rockck,
he is talking about tokenizing stock
equity. Um do you think a 247 stock
market is coming? Um do I think it's
coming? Yes. Do I think it's needed? Not
necessarily. Um I know that's not like
uh the DeFi world. I just kind of like
the idea of like, you know, weekends off
and stuff like that. Uh it's not fun
looking at particularly when there's a
liquid stuff happening on like Sunday
night in the US and prices are going
crazy. But I don't I my personal view is
like it's a foregone conclusion. Uh
whether or not everything is going to be
tokenized or some stuff will be on the
rails that we currently use is up for
debate. But there is going to be stuff.
There'll be regulations. The main thing
you need to figure out is regulations.
But you're going to have stocks, bonds,
real estate exposure, all these
different things. They're going to be
tokenized trading on the block trading
on DeFi rails blockchain. Um I I think
it's a foregone conclusion. And also you
have Larry Frink and Black Rockck
pushing for this. the benefit for them
like if you are used to buying an ETF or
a stock or anything along those lines
like you don't pay attention to like
what's going on with your the DTCC the
clearing corp or transfer agent or like
your custodian like that is kind of like
abstracted away from you but if you're
at these issuers and you're at these
platforms you know very well how all
this is working like it's very rare that
we see that come to light we saw it come
to light during the meme stock mania
with Robin Hood when they couldn't meet
things like there's a lot of plumbing on
the back end that like is just old
school. Obviously, they're using digital
stuff, but it's not on the blockchain.
Even the DTCC, the clearing corpse are
talking about using blockchain to
tokenize different things. They're
looking forward to this because it's a
lot of work. So, from Black Rockck's
perspective, it's going to decrease
cost. Like, they're already doing stuff
at cost essentially with some of their
ETFs. like if they can, you know, lower
the cost of the backend plumbing and
like save some money there, make create
efficiencies, it's the it's not exactly
there yet, but at the rate this
technology is moving, it it could get
there. So, I think it's just a foregone
conclusion that we're going to see a lot
of things tokenized. The main the main
uh hurdle right now is going to be
regulatory environment, right? So we
have all these ADRs, American depository
receipts of like, you know, Chinese
stocks and Japanese stocks trading in
the US and vice versa trading in
Australia, you name it. There's a lot of
regulatory things that go into there
around what can be wrapped into it. So
like this idea that we're just going to
take stocks, put them in the blockchain,
and everyone around the world can buy
them absent like some sort of regulatory
environment, I think, is not going to
happen. But I do think ultimately we'll
get some sort of regulatory um backdrop
that will allow this to happen. And
whether it happens in the next few years
or a decade, I think it's it's gonna
happen.
Uh well, catalyst for the next bull
market. We talked about why it's been
down. We talked about um flows being
weaker. Um you know, we had catalyst
last year, the launch of the Bitcoin
ETFs, the launch of other ETFs, change
of administration. What are we looking
forward to next? Yeah. Um, if I have to
like look for something that is the most
optimistic viewpoint, let's just stick
with Bitcoin for now because I think I
think all coins have like their own
headwinds and there's a lot of
competition there as I kind of
mentioned. But if we're just looking at
Bitcoin specifically, I look to exactly
what we were talking about those
advisers,
institutions, corporations getting on
board with a Bitcoin standard in some
way or just putting a 1 to 2%
allocation. For the most part, it's it's
I've heard of stories more and more over
the last like just the last couple weeks
and couple months of
uh advisor platforms allowing people to
buy Bitcoin ETFs. Like a lot of people
think these Bitcoin ETFs launch and it's
like okay now every adviser can just buy
them. That is not how it works. There's
a whole due diligence process.
Oftentimes it takes three years from
what many of them are accelerating them
because they want to be able to get the
Bitcoin on the platform. But even still
like initially for the most part if I if
say I'm your client I'm I mean I'm your
adviser and you're my client I can't
most places right now I can't recommend
a 1 to 2% allocation of Bitcoin in your
portfolio but if you come to me and say
I want Bitcoin in my portfolio I can do
it right because it's it's unsolicited
versus solicited. I can't solicit you to
buy this thing. um that process and and
in some cases even still even if you
come in to me and say you want to buy it
there are some places where you still
can't you can't buy the ETFs they don't
even allow it so there's kind of like
these different levels of like what you
can do and even still at the level where
you can recommend it or you can allow
people to buy it there's a lot of
restrictions you need millions of
dollars with them specifically you need
to have a high risk tolerance like so
the vast majority the trillions of
assets at these wealth platforms at
these wirehouses these brokerages they
still are not fully on board with buying
these things. Now granted, do I think
all of them are going to put a 1 to 2%
or 5% allocation to Bitcoin or crypto?
No, probably not. But even a small
portion of them doing it for a lot of
their clients, it's going to create a
lot of demand. So, I think that's the ne
next wave of demand potentially for for
Bitcoin. And and if we're talking about
other things, we're going to see index,
we already have index ETFs at launch.
Right now, they just hold Bitcoin and
Ethereum.
we're going to see by July or August,
they're going to have index funds that
are mostly Bitcoin and Ethereum, but
also holding five to eight other assets,
right? So, they're going to be I think
that will be another wave of demand
because if you're an uh adviser and
you're looking to get exposure to the
space, you're like, well, do I really
just want Bitcoin or do I want to get,
you know, an index exposure, what I'm
used to doing for stocks and bonds and
things like that. So, I think that's
another wave of demand. But overall the
regulatory environment we've gone from a
point where we were facing massive
headwinds to now we have tailwinds and
the price ironically is going the
opposite direction. So I think there's
like a disconnect between what's looking
at on the underlying fundamentals of
this industry versus what's happening
price-wise. And as we talked about the
start it's I think it's largely just
what's happening risk assets Trump
talking about tariffs all the different
things that Trump is doing uh with the
global order if you will. Do you think
we're heading into a recession? Uh I'm
definitely not qualified to answer that.
Um our economists are think there is a
chance of it at Bloomberg. Um but my
view is I think things look underlying
like the underlying fundamentals of the
economy are pretty strong. Inflation
does seem to be coming down if you look
at uh where things sit right now. Um the
right now the Fed is pricing for two
rate cuts. So obviously rates markets
aren't really pricing for a recession.
Um I don't know. I think things are
relatively strong. Um the big concern is
you know the federal deficit and and
that's what Trump and Besson and Lutnik
and you name it at the US Treasury are
focused on the US government are focused
on. Uh so no I I don't think we're
heading for a recession. I don't think
it's zero probability. I mean we had 20
plus% returns in 2023 and 2024 and going
into 2025 I was like look guys that
we're not that's not how things usually
work. We're going to be do a pullback
and I think pullbacks are healthy in the
trady markets and in the DeFi market.
So, um, yeah, recession, I don't know,
not not qualified to answer it, but I
think if we do have a recession, it
should be relatively mild just because
there's so much home equity built up in
the US specifically. Assets are up very
high. Um, I think a lot of people have
very strong balance sheets. Um, and you
see all these charts of people looking
at credit card debt and all these other
things. And kind of like what I was
saying about the Bitcoin ETFs, people
talk billions of outflows. It's like,
well, put a denominator on the amount of
debt that we're seeing in the US. And
you look at like assets and and balance
sheets of the average American and it's
like very very strong. There are some
upticks in like you know delinquencies
and mortgage rates and things like that.
It indicate a softening economy but I
don't it's hard to like kind of stop the
economy from softening once it goes in
one direction. But does that mean we're
going to go into like another 2008? I
probably not. That's my basic take.
Well earlier you talked about um
institutions buying Bitcoin ETF. So when
it was approved in 2024, we were so
excited because we were like, "Oh, now
all the institutions are going to just
buy Bitcoin spot ETF, but it seems like
it's not the case, right? Where are we
in terms of percentage possible
potential? Where are we?" Uh, we're very
early. I mean, you you have the you have
a UAE sovereign wealth fund that has
bought they're the seventh largest
holder of Black Rockck's uh IBIT, their
Bitcoin ETF. So there are institutions
coming on board as I mentioned if you
depends if you consider advisor
institutions some people do it's I kind
of think of like them in the middle
ground because it's mostly retail money
not like uh you know an endowment or
something like that um but I mean we're
starting to see c like uh one of the
European central banks is considering
adding bitcoin we have seen some uh
pension funds in the US that have
created allocations to bitcoin um so
yeah I I I think we're extremely early
the other the one thing that the
institutions A lot of them have special
mandates and they're like years long old
and they can only hold securities or
bonds or there's very strict
restrictions on what they can and cannot
buy and in many cases they can't buy the
underlying asset directly. So what
putting these putting Bitcoin in crypto
in an ETF rapper does is it makes it a
security. So it makes it much easier for
these institutions to buy. The other
thing I would say is the tax rules and
the reporting accounting rules around
Bitcoin that have been changed now
specifically you heard Michael Sailor of
Strategy or Micro Strategy talk about
this a lot that it was like very
inefficient to put it on your balance
sheet and like it's not a great thing
for tax and accounting purposes and
that's changing that has changed now or
is changing this year. So I think
there's a whole bunch of like things
that are like underlying tailwinds that
could create more demand for this asset.
But the one thing I would say is like I
work in Tradfi. I work with a lot of
people that hate Bitcoin. They hate
crypto. They hate DeFi. Oh, still a lot
of these these people in the Trady
world, they do not wrap their head
around it. They just don't like the
space. And I there's people that will
just never buy in to this. So, um I
think like this idea that everyone's
eventually going to get in. Maybe uh I'm
not fully sold on that, but it
institutions are they're here and
they're coming and they're doing their
due diligence. you can talk to these
different uh ETF issuers and they're
talking to a lot of advisors like I
sense and they're all also talking to
institutions uh but for the most part a
lot of the trady institutions I see are
doing more like special purpose things
like that basis trade so they're
involved in the markets they're trading
them they're earning spreads they're not
necessarily buying it for long-term buy
and hold hate's a very strong word they
hate it they hate it if you had to take
a wild guess what's the percentage of
Trevy people that hates Bitcoin for
example.
Oh, this might get me into trouble. I
mean, it's it's over probably a third.
Oh, that's quite a lot. Yeah, probably a
third. Yeah, I see it in with my own
company. I see it with like other
companies that we deal with like uh I
mean, Vanguard is a great example. Like,
I mean, why don't they just sell it?
Well, or short it. Yeah. Uh shorting
Bitcoin has been known to not be a great
idea particularly because it can just as
we've seen, well, I mean, it can be a
good idea. It's dropped 70% in a rather
short period of time, but it also
skyrockets. Let me just add the
narrative that just because we have
Bitcoin ETFs and other instruments, that
is a bullish case. Well, we can now
short Bitcoin using these instruments,
right? It's a two-sided sword. Yeah. I
mean, it it should make the market more
efficient. Um, people will there's I see
a lot of stuff online about it like the
market's being manipulated. I really
don't think that's the case in any way
whatsoever. Um, manipulated by whom?
What are these theories? I don't know. I
don't understand. They don't they don't
they don't make a lot of sense to me um
specifically. But yeah, you can go out
and short it. One of the hu one of the
biggest things that only happened in
November um options were allowed on
Bitcoin ETFs and they have tons of
volume. They are doing extremely well
specifically Black Rockck's
IBIT. It makes up like 98% of the option
volume in Bitcoin. And so like that's
also being heavily used. So, we're also
going to see a lot of these ETFs come to
market that are doing things kind of
like, you know, how Michael Sailor talks
about stepping up the exposure to
Bitcoin or stepping it down with his
convertible debt and preferred stock.
Like, you're kind of giving different
varying levels of exposure. There's a
lot of ETFs that have come out and are
coming out that are giving you a certain
amount of downside protection, buffer
ETFs, but to do that, you're giving up
some of your upside. You're giving
you're only going to get a portion of
the upside exposure. And there we're
seeing a bunch of demand for that in the
Bitcoin ETF space as well. So basically,
Tradfi is going to create all these
different things to get exposure to
Bitcoin in varying different ways with
financial engineering, not dissimilar to
what Michael has done with his products
uh or financial products. Uh and that's
another area of demand that I see
coming. But but for the most part, yeah,
I'm telling you like uh there's a lot of
people that just don't like crypto and
Bitcoin in general and are like unlikely
to ever get on board.
I want to get your thoughts on Michael
Sailor's new product BMAX ETF which is
um Michael Strategy Riot and Mara's
convertible bond. Yeah. So I think
that's a Rex shares product. So they are
one of the companies I was talking about
that launched a lot of those single
stock ETFs leverage products. They've
had a product Fangu that's like 3x the
fang stocks for forever. So they have a
lot of these very niche uh concentrated
often leveraged products and they have
launched this and that's another area
right so we there's going to be a lot of
ETFs that are providing exposure to
crypto or digital assets not necessarily
v via like directly directly offering
exposure but just offering exposure to
those convertible markets uh convertible
debt markets uh or like there's also
other products that have come out from
Gayscale and Bitwise and others that are
trying have filed that are basically
going to hold stocks and companies
companies that are using, you know, the
Bitcoin standard. They hold at least
$100 million in Bitcoin in their balance
sheet. So, there's all these ETFs. We
have one ETF block from Amplify. Uh they
launched in 2017, I think, and they've
held Coinbase and a lot of these other
miners and a lot of these other equity
securities that provide exposure to the
space on the equity side. So, we're
going to see a I think there's just more
demand. There's going to be a lot of
growth in the space. What happens in the
ETF space is there it's we call it a
spaghetti cannon in many cases. They
just throw a ton of stuff at the wall
and whatever sticks, they leave it up
because it's profitable. And if no one
wants it and they don't see any demand
for it coming in the future or they
don't see it filling a hole in their
offering, they just yank it. So there's
a launch of just tons of stuff at the
wall and we'll see what sticks. Does it
sound risky to you?
I mean, it's a it's it's a very
concentrated exposure. It's almost like
buying single bonds, right? So like is
buying a single bond risky? Yes, in a in
a sense because you're you're you have
idiosyncratic risk to in this case three
stocks but really one asset in many
regards. Um but like as the the main the
way that the SEC works is right they're
they're under Gary Gzler they kind of
veered away from what they were supposed
to do. The SEC is supposed to be a
disclosure regulator. They're supposed
to say, "You need to disclose all these
risks, all these potential problems down
the line, and put it all in writing so
anyone who buys it can see what they're
they're signing a contract, signing up
for this." What they aren't supposed to
do is be a merit regulator. There is
merit in this investment. There is merit
in doing this. That's not what they're
supposed to do. You're supposed to fall
within the rules, disclose everything,
and that's what all these ETFs are. Some
of those black hat ETFs I was talking
about, these leverage products. As long
as people understand what they're
getting involved in and getting getting
exposure to, I think it's fine. Uh
that's our personal view. We think it's
a the ETF industry is a big tent and
anyone can launch whatever they want to
launch. Some people want, you know, the
whole total stock market, hundreds or
thousands of stocks being held. Some
people want to hold 2x micro strategy
and bet on things going going wrong. But
the one thing I would say is if you're
playing in those markets, understand the
risks. For example, 2x long and 2x short
micro strategy. Year-to date micro
strategy not doing that great obviously
in 2025. Both the 2x long and the 2x
short are negative yearto date. Think
about that again. Both the ones that are
2x the bull 2x bullish micro strategy
and 2x bearish are both down year to
date. How does that work? Because they
reset daily. So when you have volatile
markets where you're going up and down
on a daily basis and you're going 2x on
on up and 2x down. So think about it. So
you go from 100 to 110 in the underlying
asset. You're going from 100 to 120 on
the 2x and you go back down to 100 on
the 110. You're go you're now well below
100 on the leverage one. So it's called
volatility decay just the way it resets.
And these markets are power these ETFs
or ETPs as I call them. They're power
tools. Just know that you're supposed to
hold them for long hours or something.
Oh no, you can hold some you can
depending them. So there's products that
are like 1.25 leverage now in Canada uh
from Evolve that like you could hold
those a little longer. 1.5 you might be
able to hold for a week or even 2x you
can hold for some time. The benefit is I
talked about that like if it's going up
and down you it really eats into your
return no matter what you're doing. If
it trends in one direction it actually
will outperform its stated leverage just
because it's compounding on itself. It's
like a compounding thing. So these
things are power tools. No matter what
you're doing just know what you're
getting involved in. I used to work in
ETF research. That was my first job and
I saw a bunch of really random like
themes. There was like a Christian ETF.
There was like an earthquake ETF. They
were like, "There's an UFO ETF." Um,
what was the I don't know if that UFO
ETF is still around, but what was the
most random ETF you've ever seen?
Honestly, the there's one that's been
filed from Tuttle, who is a guy that has
filed for a 2x Melania and 2X Trumpcoin
ETF. He's filed like he he's filed he's
launching an ETF that's exact UFO.
That's probably out there with the
craziest. One thing I would step back
and say is like those theme ETFs, those
Christian ETFs, they're like basically
investing in the S&P 500 and kicking out
stocks that don't meet like Christian
whatever cigarette companies, tobacco
companies, gun companies, or like
they're honestly some DEI stuff. Like so
if this company is very strong in
diversity, equity, inclusion, and ESG
stuff, they might get kicked out from
the Christian ETF. The Christian ETF, I
remember the time was just tech stock.
Yeah. Well, they have a lot of assets.
They have a lot of assets now.
Basically, you go to somebody or an
institution that is like a a church type
like institution or an endowment at a
school that is funded by the church.
They would rather do that. So, it's like
a selling point. It's a we call it in a
way like conversational alpha. Like if
I'm an adviser and I'm pitching you and
I'm telling you I put you in Bitcoin or
I put you in this. It's like a way to
like talk to you about this thing. But
also like
overall themes are very strong. People
like narratives and stories and it's
very easy to tell a story. Some of it is
very gimmicky. Some of it obvious
obviously has demand, right? So some of
those Christian and Catholic stocks,
ETFs, they're doing very well. They have
significant assets because there are
people out there that want to invest
with those values. And basically, like I
said, the ETF market is a big tent and
it tends to be a spaghetti cannon.
People have ideas. There's a lot of
people that come in and fail. It's very
capitalistic. It's very kill or get
killed. Uh we call it the the jungle. Uh
welcome to the jungle because it's very
hardcore to do well and fees tend to be
very low. You don't earn a lot of money
unless you have a lot of success. Um,
and it's, you know who it's good for?
It's good for the likes of us who are
investing in the space because we get to
benefit from all that like capitalistic
competitiveness. The Bitcoin ETS when
they launched, they launched with such
low fees, way lower than we even
expected because the fee war started
before they even launched. The weeks
leading up to the launch, you saw
everyone just dropping fees. So, we went
from 80 basis points fees now to 20. And
Grayscale has a product that's charging
15 basis points. Like that is crazy
compared to like what we see in Canada
and Europe and now the rest of the world
is kind of competing. But for the most
part, this capitalistic tendency of
people just throwing at the wall is
good for the end investor as long as you
kind of you know what you're getting
yourself into. That was great. Thanks,
James. Thank you. Thank you. Yes.